all right
[Music]
the use of vinegar for weight loss dates
back to the 1700s I did a whole chapter
about it in my book how not to dye it
entitled amping ampk the fat controller
enzyme in the body which appears to be
the mechanism behind the multitude of
beneficial metabolic effects in my 21
tweaks to accelerate weight loss I
recommend two teaspoons with every meal
which is considered safe though it
should be added to food or diluted in
water never consumes straight and
diabetics should make sure the vinegar
doesn't make their blood sugars go too
low
but that's one of the benefits of
vinegar blunting the blood sugar and
Insulin spikes after a meal and both
healthy individuals and those with blood
sugar disorders like diabetes
in a systematic review and meta-analysis
of Interventional Trials of the effects
of vinegar consumption on blood sugar
control and type 2 diabetes vinegar
improves both short-term and longer term
measures of blood sugar control and like
a little side bonus resulted in a
remarkable reduction in cholesterol to
boot and it didn't seem to matter
whether it was apple cider vinegar or
not all vinegar by definition has the
active ingredient acetic acid
so what are the implications for
clinical practice well clinicians could
incorporate vinegar consumption as part
of their dietary advice for patients
with diabetes with the caution that it
can work a little too good and so you
have to monitor closely to make sure
diabetic patients aren't over medicated
and bottom out their sugars
in my video on water purification I
talked about this study showing that the
cheapest best way to disinfect your
toothbrush so you don't have to keep
buying new ones maybe to soak it for 10
minutes and 50 white vinegar and water
so what about a vinegar sock soak for
athlete's foot or toenail fungus
foot soaks in half vinegar half water
can help anti-fungals work better but
the inconvenience of tub soaks limits
compliance so how about pouring vinegar
and water on the toes of your socks and
then just like putting your feet up for
a little while not sure how that would
be any more convenient but seem to work
in this clinician's practice
instead of vinegar for just an athlete's
foot what about vinegar for the whole
athlete the effect of vinegar
supplementation on high intensity
cycling performance they randomize
people to do two tablespoons of diluted
vinegar or sugar or both or neither and
the vinegar did nothing
is there anything else vinegar does help
with the intake of a vinegar beverage is
associated with restoration of ovulatory
function in women with polycystic ovary
syndrome for those of you unfamiliar P
costs PCOS is a major cause of irregular
menstruation and since insulin
resistance has been suggested to be one
of the causes of polycystic ovaries and
we know vinegar can improve insulin
resistance researchers decide to study
the effect of vinegar by giving seven
patients seeking a non-pharmacological
treatment for PCOS a beverage containing
a tablespoon of apple cider vinegar or
daily for a few months the insulin
resistance did improve in most but did
their Cycles return Yes in four out of
seven
before the study they were either only
having their periods every 50 days or so
or none at all or just not ovulating but
most resumed within 40 days on the
vinegar
now this doesn't prove anything but it's
at least sufficient to indicate the
possibility that it may help and what's
the downside tablespoon of vinegar would
cost less than 10 cents a day just
remember never drink vinegar straight as
it can cause second-degree caustic burns
down your throat
foreign